now in order to know why i'm farming all
of this wheat
we need to go back a little while
because i've been busy for the last
couple of days working on
well many things and let's start off
with the base well i say the base
the house on sahara street as you can
see it's no longer blank walls and
nothing else
i have spent a long time detailing that
and i actually time-lapsed the whole
thing so let's play that really quickly
you've seen me build this house last
episode but it was so undetailed that i
needed to do something about it so i
went and added windows everywhere loads
of trap doors but what you don't know
about this kind of time lapse this
represents like 20 or 30 seconds of the
video this took about two hours to do
and you know what's really annoying i
tried to use scaffolding but it's so
fiddly to try and place it in the right
way that i ended up just going back to
using dirt scaffolding in the first
place anyway
i think that went pretty well hello my
name is green and welcome back to
another episode of hermitcraft but
building that house is not the only
thing that i've been doing and it still
doesn't explain why i've got so much
wheat outside the main village
the reason is actually fairly simple i
have been gathering wheat to make bread
and i've been needing bread
to feed all the villagers because i have
repopulated the village for the second
time
using this thing and my goodness
it has spawned in so many iron golems
seriously there's iron golems out there
that have wandered about there's one two
three four five six seven here they're
all naturally spawned but guess what
most of the villagers have vanished
again
it's unbelievable seriously these
villagers do not last very long there's
one guy here that's still remaining
that's great i think there's still a
couple roaming around but i'm still yet
to figure out where they all go
like there's one here and there's one
over there i released about 20 or so and
what the heck
[Laughter]
uh looks like there's a villager stuck
in here
the salman house
oh it's not even a door
oh my goodness
no way
i think he's stuck
is this the salmon ghost making a return
oh my god oh you know what i'm not gonna
disturb this guy this is hilarious
um i'm not really sure what to do with
this because i think he's going to be
spinning on this pickle for a really
really long time
that is amazing and the fact that you
can see him from like any angle
so there is uh officially more iron
golems than villagers here but there is
a few roaming around which is a really
good sign
but it looks like yeah more more
breeding has to happen i must say that
the 114 village really is growing and it
is it's really becoming a really cool
little micro community like all the
hermits obviously have all the blocks
that they need to build anything and
that's just great another thing that i
thought i would do while i was here oh
i've got a visitor green you've got a
friend
you got you got a friend hold on bread
do you guys want some bread rendog says
yo gee
hold on
another thing that i did was i went
mining oh yes it's happening
i'm just gonna i'm just gonna keep
repopulating in here
why not
they're not going anywhere i mind a load
of diamond ores and there's a quick
time-lapse over there i didn't last
particularly long but you know how i
feel about diamonds there's something
about this particular block that's just
magnificent so let's see how many
diamonds we get out of this
oh pretty good pretty good pretty good
43 diamonds not bad that oh the child
can totally open doors
excuse me
no
bad
you're just like your dad you are
well there goes that idea but at least
you know i could just keep throwing
these guys bread to be honest that's why
i got all this wheat in the first place
so
i'm basically gonna have to keep up
with uh giving all of the villagers
loads of bread so that we can
keep the population high enough to
sustain itself if we lose all the
villagers that's it
ah that was that's a good little top up
for my diamonds
well we've got some of the villagers
here they're all sleeping over here
maybe i can just give them bread ahead
of time they should pick all that up
none of the villagers are sleeping here
anymore so this is this is a wreck
well since we're still the biggest house
on sahara street i don't feel any
inclination to build any more on this
because
i'm actually really really proud of this
one i think it looks
magnificent with all of the details now
added i dare i say it this is like one
of my favorite builds of the season like
maybe not my main base but it's really
refreshing to build in a different style
whereas mumbo he's gone for well he's
gone for the same style that he's been
doing the rest of the season i've really
enjoyed this i love the way this all
fits together
but as we close up the rest of this
little farm here because i'm gonna need
as much bread as possible
i actually think it's time to head back
to the old lands
and have a little meeting with either
mumbo or iskall or both of them and we
need to work out
what exactly we're going to do for the
grand opening of sahara because as far
as i'm aware
it works
we just need to open it
let's head back now and see what's going
on
holy moly
zuma's been
doing some work
that looks amazing
the way that this looks like with all
the skyscrapers
beginning with uh scaffolding this is
amazing
so last episode we set up the red ribbon
in order to get the what the heck
i made this red ribbon for the grand
opening it's coming soon
but it looks like there's already a line
oh my goodness what's this
so that there's falsey first in line
then there's people saying why is it
taking so long then there's a family of
phantoms
i'm bored mommy it's like when a big
corporation releases a new product that
people are really excited about or like
a new book that everyone's been waiting
for and they line up outside overnight
that's exactly what this feels like i
think sahara has has uh done its job of
creating some hype but as far as i'm
aware
there's still potatoes stuck in the
system so i'm just gonna leave that for
now right hopefully i can get hold of
mumbo and iskall and we'll have a quick
little meeting to decide what to do
sahara is
brilliant
what
does that mean
it's brilliant it is brilliant i mean
what what do you mean by what does that
mean it's
look around have you not seen it well i
know that but from a technical report i
don't know what that means
does it mean it's working completely and
flawlessly
it just means that it's brilliant
also don't actually read that book i
lost the real book
this this oh see now here's
see now right okay
i mean you you're coming in here you're
blasting us for our tech report writing
but you don't even have the decency to
keep hold of the tech report
this book has exactly the same content
as the one that we had so well okay so
sahara is brilliant okay and i think we
remember i i think i think we said that
it was going to be finished soonish as
well um
which was suitably accurate i would say
um yeah there was a few problems but
we've we've patched well i've patched up
some of them iska has been doing some
work as well i think
i think sahara is now
fantastic yeah i i can fantasize
already is it fantastic
it is i love i love the world it's
fantastic you know
this tech report really yeah this really
does say everything here i look take a
look
says
i found it in the eye trade center
[Laughter]
well all right so why don't we go and
see if it actually works come on let's
go and see it in action
okay
see i knew i was onto something escal by
making that massive hole in there oh you
still haven't fixed it
for goodness sake
of course i haven't fixed it
i've been saying it's just a bold
architectural decision there's also a
bit of a queue outside i don't know if
you guys have seen i added this like red
ribbon for the grand opening
uh but there's actually oh nice yeah
there's a queue outside we're we're
legit my goodness we're like a big
corporation all right come on then show
me show me how this works um okay yeah
the lights stuck i don't know what's
going on there but they're stuck on the
same oh no someone sent stuff here
oh
yeah we have no stock at the moment this
is what this shows uh right
someone must have shown something in the
system
i have not i've not by the second lamp
means that it's failed no it's found a
decoder and then it's failed to shoot
out the shulker box that's weird so it
must have been an item that wasn't in
the system what's that so you're telling
me that it's broken
well no it's not broken it's just just
someone sent an item in that shouldn't
be sent in to the system oh
that's um
not good
yeah green yeah
i think i know what broke have you been
pushing okay is there um you know what
i'm just gonna head back here
we said do not touch
any of the redstone we can make a roller
coaster for you but don't touch any reds
i didn't touch any redstone
i didn't go anywhere near the redstone i
was just looking around trying to make
it work um is there a chest back here by
any chance somewhere
no no what do you mean what are you
looking for
oh my god is there there's a dropper
here is that something to do with it oh
no no what about here no
no
okay great
i suspected this all right i've been
reading through my youtube comments okay
and i've heard news about a certain spud
that has entered the sahara system okay
and i feel like that spud might actually
have your name on it yeah
it doesn't have my name on it it still
says baked potato i thought i could just
make it work because there was no i
heard you guys had finished from the
tech report so i was like oh you know
sahara didn't say we didn't say finish
we said brilliant yeah so it's brilliant
doesn't mean i thought that meant
finished so i was like oh yeah what if i
just throw it on he's done it again
i mean it's broken okay
[Laughter]
real question though how do we de-potato
the sahara machine
we're laughing i don't know we didn't
plan for this um we're gonna have to
rebuild all of it right okay see you in
three months
get back here and get that potato out of
the machine
oh so it's all the way over here
somewhere yes it goes all the way your
potato has traveled far far and wide
what if a customer decides to throw
stuff in there
it doesn't it won't matter because
what do you mean first
they're not five-year-olds
yeah well they're not five-year-olds and
uh the system will be locked like the
decoders will be will be filtered
oh my
yep there it is
there's a lot of junk in here i found i
found
what is all that
there was a potato jamming the entire
thing
i'm going to keep this potato forever we
had a spud jam
[Laughter]
right well this begs the question since
we're actually in the stock room at the
moment what are we going to stock sahara
with because the grand opening is
obviously coming soon-ish
and we can't open the whole thing
because there's far too many items so we
need to choose very carefully
just a select few items to sell sand
obviously sand
i feel like i'm the only one that can't
do that
you can do it try it
i'm just getting no i'm too nervous i've
gone for stage fright okay i'm standing
behind this
[Music]
this is why green is the receptionist
okay so sand what else
what else do people really want
rockets maybe
yeah not ice pockets
pockets uh golden potatoes golden no
golden carrots not potatoes no
we're not having more we're not having
more spa jams all right
okay eyes okay and the pearls but no no
ice why would we sell ice
golden carrots
yep
rocky rockets
sand and then we need something else why
end up
podzol
pod why podca glowstone blocks well yeah
we could see we could sell we could sell
the things that your witch farm makes
like redstone yep redstone gunpowder
there we go
the only the only problem is that the
only two people who buy redstone would
be you you and me well let's
you know not worry about that we've got
things to sell so we've got to get
supply and demand yeah okay just supply
all right there we go
we've got enough items but
we're a bit limited by something at the
moment
oh yeah
i mean you guys told me we needed an
insane amount of shulker boxes so i went
end busting for it and i got a few but
you told me we need like this gal told
me we needed 1 400 or something
ridiculous
yep i got like 100 shelter boxes yeah so
originally i think we needed 1 400 i
think now with the re
the changing of the system
how many how many shulker boxes
how many people i don't know i haven't
[Music]
a lot so plan of action shulker boxes
grand opening it's happening
when
soon that's good mumbo that's that's
like brilliant he's getting there he's
starting to maybe he's the new tech lead
we need to get him home really
yay
how did you have that so on demand
hard hat
i'm sahara dude right it blends in too
much with your hair make sure the
machine is potato proof gonna go
if i can shut down sahara with one
potato you guys aren't doing your job
properly i'm just saying i'll chuck it
in here who gave him a hard hat where
did it go
eric there it goes bye bye potato well i
mean that could have been worse that's
just going to sit there now so someone's
going to get a potato oh that's horrible
whoa that's bad brienne who no you ruin
it yay
make make him win make him win
oh yeah no this doesn't mean that he's
going to persevere doesn't it oh no
i got to find a new place he's thinking
where can i jam a potato that is really
going to break tomorrow
i just want to prove a point there it
goes it's off oh it's disappeared
someone
i want that potato on my desk by morning
[Laughter]
all right so so so by soon do we mean
just soon are we saying vaguely soon
vaguely soon hopefully within the next
week but no promises who knows
there might be a potato fiend in sahara
okay should we put that on on
advertising material will open hopefully
soon potentially within this week
possibly maybe maybe yeah look forward
to it perfect yeah all right then so we
have a pretty good plan to get sahara
open and done with meaning that this
ribbon will be coming down
soon
the reason we're not giving an exact
date is because we just don't know how
long it's going to take but one thing
that i've been wanting to do for a
really really long time is just make the
entrance to this a little bit nicer
looking because it is just grass at the
moment and i can see that false has like
added a little trail here but i want to
add something a little bit more official
to this
just so that it's ready for the grand
opening nothing too over the top just a
big straight line of concrete
now if i destroy the blocks underneath
these armor stands
is that gonna ruin anything
the last thing i want to do is get rid
of the customers we have in line it
looks okay it looks like they stay in
the air
i took a risk and it was worth it
oh no
oh i was so wrong
this just keeps getting worse i've just
i'm just digging myself a hole why is
there so much sand here okay right well
i have to do this the difficult way now
so what i'm gonna do is just keep
placing this
and uh eventually push it all the way
back up to the top
and last one
ow
what why are you spitting at me no
bad llama
bad llama that was an absolute nightmare
there's still not in the right place but
it's it's better than nothing
at least i've somewhat fixed it you know
i'm just gonna leave it like that
i can't put water on this track because
otherwise it's gonna push all the armor
stands and i don't want to get rid of
our customers add a few vegetation
decorations on the side and then we can
roll out the red carpet well most of the
red carpet
for all of the people visiting
there we go the red carpet has been
rolled out it's looking very christmassy
which wasn't my intention
but i would say that this definitely
helps promote the fact that there is
a bit of a to do
with sahara and hopefully this will
start gathering some attention if it
doesn't we're definitely gonna have to
go and remind everyone about the grand
opening because we need some of our
fellow hermits here to buy some of our
stuff
but i think that pretty much does it for
sahara until the grand opening of course
i am gonna go and have to
go end busting with iska and mumbo at
some point we're gonna have to organize
that and then when we have enough
shulker boxes there's absolutely no
reason why we don't open
finally and more people have tried out
my course i know that xi zuma void has
tried it and ren has tried it with a
terrible score of two minutes 44.
that's that's almost double mine that's
pretty terrible and the diamonds
are coming in at a magnificent rate
this is really good news because i can
take this business idea to vex tank
which is scars and cubs little adventure
thing it's kind of like dragon's den or
shark tank where you propose a business
idea and then they decide whether
they're going to give you financial
backing
if we take the idea to them maybe
they'll give us some diamonds
to set up the company
but for now let's head back to the 114
village
because i'm guessing that enough time
has passed that all the villagers have
disappeared again
all right we're back
and it looks like there's still tons of
iron golems
so many iron golems i don't even know
what to do with all these oh my goodness
something's not right here
something's definitely not right here
i guess we could just kill them for some
iron but that doesn't make any sense
we'll just leave them there
and
oh
no
oh no
ah
well it was inevitable wasn't it he's
right here mumbo is right there
look at this
my house is still intact but iskal he
hasn't even both this is is this
cheating
this has got to be cheating right he
hasn't done anything to his house here
he's just built a new house
and attached it to a up balloon
this is ridiculous it's even this is
definitely an up house
oh my goodness he's actually designed it
in very disney fashion
oh my goodness so
does this count is this
is this fair i suppose there are no
rules
there's no rules on this
so
oh it makes my house look small now
and what's mumbo been doing sorry what
is going on here
mumbo has built his house taller than
mine he's got like a platform and he's
made hold on
he's he's encroaching on my space he's
attached he's attached this platform to
my chimney
i said i did say that there were no
rules this is just sort of sprung up out
of nowhere
he's blocking me
he's totally trying to block me
there's no no there's no way there's no
way that this can happen i'm just going
to build around this
mark my words mumbo
this house this house building
competition has only just started i'll
get round this
tower that you've made
but i think
i think we've got to do something about
this because
that like at least mumbo's playing fair
game right his is attached all the way
to the ground
this gal has got a big gap
so
i think next episode
we've got to bring this down to where it
should be
and we'll figure that out next episode
i cannot believe this
ah
looks like the building competition has
officially begun
and i'm gonna have to build my tower up
and beyond and above that
ah well i'm afraid that's it for me
everybody thank you very much for
watching whoa
whoa what's this vibration
look at this
also here is a very quick trick that we
pulled on mumbo at the end of our sahara
recording i've put this trick on several
people and it's amazing how often this
works so let me let me take you in on it
so basically what you do is you say to
your friends do you want to see a magic
trick and they say yes in minecraft and
you tell them to you tell them to look
at you and you press f1 and you log out
and it looks like you vanish instantly
this is what happened when we did this
to mumbo right right look look read in
the eye
look at us
what
that's really fun
that's really really funny
i'm upset that i wasn't recording then
because that's really funny
[Laughter]
that's a hilarious trick